SUSHEEL RAAI

+44 7760204953 ♦ raai.susheel@gmail.com ♦ 12 G/L Denhead Crescent, Dundee, DD2 4SL

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/susheelraai
- https://github.com/SusheelRaai95

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

A proficient and reliable developer with a strong background of more than 6 years of experience in writing production-ready, testable and secure code. Experienced in using various technologies and tools, such as C#, .NET, Angular, Azure. A proactive and collaborative team member who communicates effectively and seeks to improve processes and outcomes.

SKILLS

C# ASP.NET Angular **HTML** Microsoft Azure Security principles and practices

SQL Server ASP.NET MVC JavaScript **CSS GIT** NUnit testing frameworks

MySQL **ASP.NET WEB API** jQuery Bootstrap GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JISC / HESA Aug 2022 - Present

Software Developer

A versatile and collaborative software developer with a solid background in agile development and scrum methodology. Skilled in planning, designing, coding, testing and documenting programs based on requirements and specifications. Experienced in working with HESA systems and adhering to agreed standards, patterns, architectures and constraints. Proficient in debugging and resolving issues in applications and facilitating the build and release capability. A proactive and continuous learner who keeps up to date with technologies and practices.

Accomplishments:

- Developed leadership skills by leading, mentoring junior staff, facilitating effective communication and collaboration, and resolving conflicts and challenges.
- Developed teamwork skills by participating in various team meetings, contributing to the shared goals and outcomes, respecting and supporting other team members, and giving and receiving constructive
- Keeping up to date with technologies and practices through on the job training, interaction with coworkers and self-learning.
- Developed diversity and inclusion skills by engaging with people from different backgrounds, cultures and perspectives, learning from their experiences and insights, promoting a culture of respect and belonging, and challenging any bias or discrimination I encounter.
- Created and used a CI/CD pipeline in Azure DevOps to automate the build, test and deployment of my web application to Azure App Service, using Git as the source control and Azure Resource Manager as the deployment tool.

 Employed TTD development and delivered high-quality software with reduced defect rates, improving overall design and productivity.

ZENQ Sept 2018 - Dec 2020

Software Developer

A strong expertise in developing business-critical applications and experience in writing reusable components. Implemented APIs and RESTful services, and converted JavaScript applications to Angular applications. Skilled in creating project designs, web applications, user stories and prototypes based on the client's requirements. Adept in coordinating with the testing team, resolving bugs, designing pipelines and leading the project deployment.

Accomplishments:

- Substantial work experience in Database design and development, for creating complex database queries, writing constraints, indexes, views, stored procedures and functions in Microsoft SQL Server.
- Strong experience in developing and consuming ASP.NET web APIs to increase development workflow.
- Carefully documented technical workflows, using records for training new staff. Conducted rigorous root-cause analyses and investigations to identify and correct software issues.
- Deployed new front-end features using Angular with UI library components like Angular Material. Experience in developing Single Page Applications using various Angular versions in visual code.

SATYA TECHNOLOGIES April 2017 - Feb 2018

Intern

An intern with a deep understanding of Object Oriented Programming (OOP) concepts and SOLID principles. Experienced in process modelling using UML, Sequence Diagrams, Flowcharts, Activity Diagrams and use cases using UMLet tool. Skilled in writing unit tests using NUnit testing framework to ensure the quality and functionality of user interfaces and back-end processing. Knowledgeable in web technologies such as HTML, HTML5, XHTML, XML and JavaScript.

Accomplishments:

- Extensive experience with Object Oriented Programming OOPS concepts and SOLID principles.
- Good experience in process modelling using UML, Sequence Diagrams, Flowcharts, Activity Diagrams and use cases using UMLet tool.
- Wrote 1000+ unit tests to verify functionality of user interfaces and back-end processing using NUnit testing framework.

EDUCATION

University of East Anglia

Feb 2021 - Feb 2022

MSc Data Science, Computer Science

CMR College of Engineering and Technology (JNTUH)

Sept 2014 - Jun 2018

Computer Science and Engineering